Privacy Policy
==============

### Pixilart http://www.pixilart.com ("Site")

#### Pixilart respects each individual's right to personal privacy.

We will collect and use information through our website only in the way disclosed in this statement. This statement applies solely to information collected at http://www.pixilart.com ("Site") and may not apply to information we collect about you offline (such as over the phone) or in different situations (such as through email correspondence).

Please take a few moments to read this privacy policy. By accessing the Pixilart Network, you acknowledge that this privacy policy applies to only the services of the Pixilart Network.

#### Parental Information

Pixilart is a child safe website. There are swearing filters enabled and options to block users. There are no private conversations - every conversation is public. All drawings are reviewed and removed if they are not all-age appropriate. Pixilart is a place for art, learning and socializing.

#### Age Limit

Pixilart is for all ages. Information we collect and use is as worded inside this privacy policy statement. We require parental consent for children under 13 years of age. Information on this website is monitored and removed if it is not socially acceptable for all ages.

#### Children’s Information

We do not intend children under 13 years of age to use our website without a parent’s consent. We will collect information and accept registration, but some content might not be suitable for all ages. Reported content is reviewed and removed upon further inspection if it does not meet our all-ages criteria.

#### Data We Collect

The Data we collect is to help provide excellent services that will improve your experience on Pixilart. Data we collect is to identify you, such as your name, e-mail address, and username.

Our systems only gather "Basic Personal Information" ("Personal Data") such as "e-mail, username, first name, and last name" (first & last name are not required). Your e-mail is used to access your account, notification e-mails and promotional e-mails.

If you use Pixilart and create an account via third party applications such as 'Facebook' or 'Twitter' - we collect just the basics of information which must be approved before the account creation is completed. We cannot alter or see the information on those third party applications. Pixilart will not post any content to Facebook or Twitter without your permission.

We collect and use your Personal Data when you register for special services (e.g. news, notifications). We use your Personal Data to help customize advertising and content available on the Pixilart Network, to send you information about notifications, alerts, news, products, and services.

#### Non-Personal Identifiable Data (e.g. IP address, hardware information)

Our servers will automatically record such data to help understand how a person operates and performs on the website to help improve and track components that are listed below. This data is logged and referenced by our administration team.

#### Use of Data

Data may be used to customize and improve your user experience on this site. Efforts will be made to prevent your data from being made available to third parties unless (i) provided for otherwise in this Privacy Policy; (ii) your consent is obtained, such as when you choose to opt-in or opt-out for the sharing of data;(iii) a service provided on our site requires interaction with a third party, or is provided by a third party, such as an application service provider; (iv) pursuant to legal action or law enforcement; (v) it is found that your use of this site violates the site editor's policy, terms of service, or other usage guidelines, or if it is deemed reasonably necessary by the site editor to protect the site editor's legal rights and/or property; or (vi) this site is purchased by a third party, in which case that third party will be able to use the data in the same manner as set forth in this policy.

In the event you choose to use links displayed on this website to visit other websites, you are advised to read the privacy policies published on those sites. Pixilart uses third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to not having this information used by these companies, [click here](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1).

#### Uploading User Images

Pixilart provides an optional feature that allows users to upload images from their device to our app. When you choose to use this feature, your images will be transmitted from your device to our secure AWS S3 server, where they will be stored. We do not collect any metadata about the uploaded images.

#### Account Creation (Sign up) & Deactivate your account

Creating an account is completely free. We collect Personal Data, which is used to access your account, allow other registered users to search you, send notification e-mails and promotional e-mails. You can deactivate your account if you decide to longer use Pixilart. Deactivating your account prevents anyone from viewing your account until it is re-activated. You can re-activate your account by logging back in. If you wish to prevent Google and other search engines from viewing your account or drawings - you can 'Deactivate' your account in your [settings](https://www.pixilart.com/settings/deactivate). You can also set your drawings to private or delete your drawings to prevent search engine indexing.

#### Retention of Data

Pixilart will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the performance of the services provided by the Site. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

Uploaded images will be securely stored on our AWS S3 server. We take appropriate measures to ensure that your data is protected against unauthorized access, alteration, or destruction. We will not share your images with any third-party services or individuals unless this is necessary to provide our services to you.

In relation to Personal Data of your profile, we will retain the same as long as your account with us is still active. If you choose to [close](https://www.pixilart.com/settings/delete) your account or if your account is closed, we will delete your Personal Data and information within thirty (30) days.

#### Removing User Images

Pixilart understands that individual privacy is important and so we give users the option to remove their uploaded images from our app. You have the right to ask us to delete any of your personal data, including uploaded images, which you have provided to us. We will promptly respond to any such requests in a reasonable timeframe.

#### Cookie Data

Like many Internet sites, we use “cookies” to collect information. Pixilart uses cookies to collect information to track usage. Cookie tracking is used to monitor views on all photo types. Cookie sessions are used to store account data locally or on the server side for your conveniences. Other cookies may be used by advertising and third party tools/resources.

Advertisements may display on this website and, if so, may set and access cookies on your computer; such cookies are subject to the privacy policy of the parties providing the advertisement. However, the parties providing the advertising do not have access to this site's cookies. These parties usually use non-personally-identifiable or anonymous codes to obtain information about your visits to this site.

For more information about this type of online advertising, about cookies, and about how to turn this feature off, please visit [this link](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1).

Please note that turning off advertising cookies won’t mean that you are not served any advertising, merely that it will not be tailored to your interests.

#### Advertising

This Site is affiliated with Freestar for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site, and Freestar will collect and use certain data for advertising purposes. To learn more about Freestar's data usage, [click here](https://freestar.com/privacy-policy/).

#### Analytics services

We use third-party analytics services to collect information about your session including browser, location (city, state, country), user ID (if signed in) to understand the interaction between the website and user. We may disclose your site use information to these analytics providers to help us learn more about how you and others use our services: [Google Privacy & Terms](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). To learn more about how Facebook uses your data, log on to your Facebook account and access your settings, or visit [https://www.facebook.com/help/325807937506242](https://www.facebook.com/help/325807937506242) To learn more about Firebase, visit [https://firebase.google.com/support/privacy](https://firebase.google.com/support/privacy)

#### Security

We cannot guarantee the information we collect is completely secure. The Internet and its ability to transmit data isn't flawless, and there is no current method of guaranteeing complete security. However, we will do our best to protect and secure your information.

#### Artwork Privacy

Pixilart has an option to set images to 'private', 'unlisted', and 'public'. Private images are images that only the account creator and admins can see. Setting a drawing to private will prevent Google and other search engines from indexing that drawing. Unlisted images are protected images that are only viewable by URL. Public images are images that show in profile and public galleries.

#### When We Might Disclose Information

As part of our regular business conduct, we may share information with companies or individuals providing services or acting on our behalf, such as companies providing technological or fulfillment services. In the event that there is a change of corporate ownership, the new owners will of course be provided with our files, including information you have submitted. We will also share information with government officials, including law enforcement officials or court authorities, in order to cooperate with a legitimate investigation.

Unless we tell you first (such as at the time we collect information from you), or unless it is part of a specific program or feature in which you have elected to participate, we do not share personally identifiable information that we have collected (such as name or email address) with other third-party companies for their own commercial or marketing purposes.

#### California Privacy Rights

The State of California has established its own unique regulations that apply to California residents. If you reside in California, you have the right to obtain from us, once per year and free of charge, information regarding what information we disclose to third party marketers, and the names and addresses of each third party to whom we disclose your data. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please use the contact information listed below.

If you are a California resident and under the age of 18, you have the right to request that we remove any data that you publicly post on our website. To request removal of your data, please use the contact information listed below. Note that while we will remove your data that is publicly posted on our website, we may not be able to completely remove that data from our systems.

#### Common ID Cookie

This site uses cookies and similar tracking technologies such as the Common ID cookie to provide its services. Cookies are important devices for measuring advertising effectiveness and ensuring a robust online advertising industry. The Common ID cookie stores a unique user id in the first party domain and is accessible to our ad partners. This simple ID that can be utilized to improve user matching, especially for delivering ads to iOS and MacOS browsers. Users can opt out of the Common ID tracking cookie by clicking [here](#opt-out).

#### Advertising Privacy Settings

FOR EU USERS ONLY: When you use our site, pre-selected companies may access and use certain information on your device and about your interests to serve ads or personalized content. You may revisit or change consent-choices at any time by clicking [here](#cmp).

#### Questions

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our policies, please contact us at:

E-mail: [\[email protected\]](https://www.pixilart.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Last updated: May 29, 2023
